(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T12:35:06.530254",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Nanashi Mumei 3D Showcase
[Nanashi Mumei 3D Showcase #MOOMin3D]
Oh, hi.
It's me, Nanashi Mumei in 3D!
Oh my goodness!
I, I should probably stand up.
Ta-da!
Yes, ohayou, ohayou, ohayou, ohayou!
Good day! Good morning, good evening!
Get out of bed!
We are mumming in the 3D today!
Oh, I'm so excited!
But I'm also really nervous.
I am not used to being uh watched this way.
Um, but it's okay.
I'm just really happy to be here
and that I can finally be 3D after 2 years.
Um, yeah, but before we start, before
Before we really get into things,
um, may I bring your attention to
may I bring your attention to...
this?
The hashtag!
Yes, yes, yes, we have a hashtag for 3D, it is MOOM in 3D.
Yes, we have a hashtag for 3D,it's MOOM in 3D!
Yes, capital M O O M, lowercase i n 3, capital D, with the hashtag before that, 'cause that's how hashtags work!
Yes, capital M-O-O-M, lowercase i-n-3,capital D, with the hashtag before it!
Yes, if you uh have any thoughts or any screenshots you want to share, please, please use that, and maybe I can look later, other people can look.
If you have any thoughts or screenshotsto share, please use that hashtag.
Uh yeah, yeah, be a bunch of fun!
It'll be a bunch of fun!
Um, yes! I'm really here
Yes, I'm really here
in 3D, hello!
Uh, would you guys like a closer look pe- perhaps?
Would you guys like a closer look, perhaps?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Not there, not there.
Uh, how about we start with the toes?
How about we start with the toes?
Just kidding, I have shoes on.
They're cute shoes, aren't they?
Aren't they?
They protect the toes.
Nice, nice, right?
And me also have oh, yes, yes, let's appreciate it.
And we also have—oh, yes,let's appreciate it!
Let's appreciate it. What exactly, you know what?
Let's appreciate it. What exactly?You know what?
My yes, uh take your screenshots now because we have to keep going, we have to keep going.
Take your screenshots now becausewe have to keep going!
Look, look, look, look, look, look, look.
Look, look, look, look, look.
My accessories, I have my satchel.
My accessories—I have my satchel.
I have my lantern, it is a miracle I have not set myself on fire with this thing.
I have my lantern. It's a miracleI haven't set myself on fire with it.
Um, and then of course I have my dagger.
And then of course, I have my dagger.
You didn't forget about my dagger, did you?
Uh, well, if you did, you might want to work on improving your memory and your survival skills.
Well, if you did, you might want to workon your memory and survival skills.
Um, let's see, going up a bit, a bit. Yes, my my bow, my bow, right?
Let's see, going up a bit...Yes, my bow, right?
You like my You like my bow, right? And then yes, my face!
You like my bow, right?And then yes, my face!
Hello, hello!
Yes, you've now seen me in full 3D.
What the fu-
What the fu—
You've seen too much. You've seen too much.
You've seen too much!You've seen too much!
I'm just kidding, but I wanted to show you guys.
I'm just kidding, but I wantedto show you guys.
Look, my dagger.
It's functional.
I can use it. I remember how to use it.
Standing back as the power of Council in 3D on my side.
Standing back as the Power of Councilin 3D on my side.
I'll shoot- oh I'm not supposed to point it at you guys.
I'll shoot—oh, I'm not supposedto point it at you guys.
Oopsie.
Uh, let me just put it back. Oopsie.
Let me just put it back. Oopsie.
Oh, was that too scary?
Oh no, was that too scary?
Oh, oh, do we have some babies in the chat?
Oh, do we have some babies in the chat?
Oh no, the poor babies, I better calm them down here.
Oh no, the poor babies!I better calm them down.
Watch this, watch this!
Peekaboo!
See? Cute, right?
Cute, cute, cute, cute, cute!
Should I show you around my treehouse? You guys have seen it in 2D a lot, but this is your first time seeing it in 3D.
Should I show you around my treehouse?You've seen it in 2D, but not in 3D.
There's a lot to share, come here, come here, come here.
There's a lot to share. Come here!
What do we got? We got caffeine.
Oh, don't show Bae. Bae don't watch.
Oh, don't show Bae.Bae, don't watch!
Um, yes, we have caffeine. We have a Kronii's hourglass up there.
We have caffeine. We haveKronii's hourglass up there.
You guys remember that.
Uh, what else do we have? Oh, we have
What else do we have? Oh, we have
the first friend that we ever made.
Here, and here, you remember him, don't you?
Right here. You remember him, don't you?
And we have some of uh Faunas things. I uh I I'm not sure what.
And we have some of Fauna's things...I'm not sure what.
I also have a heart or something, I think.
Um, but yes, oh we also have my fire. Nice and toasty, nice and warm, right?
But yes, we also have my fire.Nice and toasty, nice and warm, right?
And we have my berry tree right above it.
And we have my berry treeright above it.
Totally not a fire hazard.
Totally safe, unless we have berries all year round.
Totally safe, as long as we haveberries all year round.
Oh, over here,
we have my desk.
Usually I have my PC here, but for the sake of the stream, uh I threw it away.
Usually I have my PC here, but forthe sake of the stream, I threw it away.
So, let's see.
We have a map here.
We have Bae's dice.
We have uh IRyS's compass, or I guess the compass I made with parts of IRyS, or something.
We have IRyS's compass—or I guessa compass made with parts of IRyS.
And oh the pictures don't don't worry about those windows. Those those those those don't look into anywhere. Don't worry, don't worry.
And the pictures—don't worry aboutthose windows, they don't look anywhere.
Oh I have some books here.
Yes, very very important books about light, height, sky, abyss, hypothesis, and humans, that's pretty important.
Very important books about light, height,sky, abyss, hypothesis, and humans!
As guardian of civilization, I should probably have a book about those. They're out of order, aren't they? Don't worry about it, don't worry about it.
As guardian of civilization, I shouldhave books about those. Don't worry about it.
Um, let's go over here. Come here, come here.
Let's go over here. Come here!
I have more stuff. Oh, I have my
bedroom, but no one cares about that, right?
bedroom, but no one cares about that!
Don't worry about that where I sleep? Who cares?
Don't worry about where I sleep.Who cares?
Uh, but over here we have the outside.
But over here, we have the outside.
Look at that view! Oh my goodness, I could never get sick of that.
Look at that view! Oh my goodness,I could never get sick of that.
Okay, let's go back inside now. Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Okay, let's go back inside now.Let's go, let's go!
Um, yeah actually that's about it. That is the tree house. Smaller than you thought, huh?
Actually, that's about it. That is thetreehouse—smaller than you thought, huh?
But it's perfect for me. Nice and cozy.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh. Friend!
Oh, oh, oh... Friend!
You little bag of sunshine, how are you?
You want you want to say hi?
Do you want to say hi?
Wait, why are you so angry?
What? Do you have something to say?
Go ahead, say it.
Go ahead.
What is it?
Yeah. That's what I thought.
That's what I thought.
Know your place.
Know your place. Get out of here.
Get out of here!
Sorry, I have to be stern with him.
He tried taking over the world again the other day.
Ah, it's such a... Such a pain in the... No, he's, he's fine.
Oh, what's this?
Oh, oh, Hoot-san! Oh, my precious!
It's the little Hoot-san! Look at you,
so cute and so good!
What's going on? Are you trying to say something?
What is it?
Come on.
Did a human fall down the well?
No.
All right, you can't talk either. No one in here can talk except me. I...
Right, right. Um...
Well, how about we play a game to figure out what it is you're trying to say,
and how about we use some hints with your little Hootsie prints?
Let's do that.
Got any silly shoes out there? Come on in!
Hmm. I think I could use some help, though. Does anyone in the audience volunteer?
Hello?
Me! Me!
Me, me, me, me, me! Yeah, you. Me, me, you, funny-looking kid!
Me, me? Yeah, you. Who are you?
I'm I, I, I'm Gura, Gura...
Gura as in Gura cheese! Hello, Gura cheese.
You're just the person I need for this. Can you help me find Hootsie's Footsies?
Yes! Yes! All right.
Gura cheese.
Let me explain it to you. Okay, Hootsie here...
has left prints around the tree house.
And we have to find where he left prints on, and that's how we will know what he's trying to tell us.
We'll have to guess at the end once we find everything.
Decoding Hootsie's secret.
Secret. Do you have the brain for it? I hope so. I believe in you.
All right. Let's start taking a look around.
Hootsie's Footsies, Hootsie's Footsies, Hootsie's Footsies.
Speaking of feet, should we start from the ground up?
Smart.
Footsies, where the footsies go? Footsies, footsies, footsies, footsies go, footsies, footsies.
Hey, wait.
Huh? What?
What's that? On the rope.
That thing? Oh, oh, there there. There's rope, there's red on the rope.
Oh, you found one! It's a Footsie! It's a Footsie! Nice.
Hootsie's Footsies. So weird-looking knot.
But okay, rope, rope, knot, who knows?
Okay, we have and not. Oh, okay. So we have one clue.
Let's continue looking. A rope is a clue? I need your... I need your shark vision.
My shark vision? Or smell? Or not smell, smell, smell not?
You're good at that? Rope? Um, let's look up here.
Okay. Um, what about my bookshelf?
You? I have a lot of stuff here. You must have left a print on one of these.
You have a lot of bottles, emptied glass jars.
I do. You want one? Yeah.
Okay, you can have one. And you have bread, too. Yummy.
Oh, yeah, my bread. I've had it for a few years. Oh, don't ask whose eggs those are.
Eggs? Oh, footsy!
Bread? Footsy! Bread!
Uh, cut, cut, uh, scissors! That's what they're called, scissors.
Oh, wait, wait, you're at the scissor, the scissors! Let's see.
I think that's a footsy, or is it blood? Wait.
Blood?
What do you think? I hope it's a footsy. I don't know how to respond if it's blood.
Ah, it looks like jam. So I'm pretty sure it's a footsy.
All right, so scissors and rope, rope. We have rope. We have scissors.
Scissors? Probably one more clue, right? Cause rule of threes.
That's how you know it's good writing. Okay, um...
Scissors and rope. I don't think there's anything else on the bookshelf.
Scissors and rope tie us,
And together they make...
Rope not required,
A ship not required.
Ah, that's the monkey's fit.
What?
I thought I saw Hootie, but it's behind me now.
What is-- what is that?
Oh, what is that?
Oh, I don't-- Oh,
What are those doing there? Those should be in my pocket.
Oh, it's--
Oh, it's
It's handcuffs.
There's hand-- handcuffs.
That's a-- Where's handcuffs?
Wait, wait, wait.
Rope?
Scissors?
And handcuffs.
Handcuffs.
What's-- What's he? What's he?
What's he doing to himself?
Handcuffs?
Well, here, let's go-- let's go back here.
Well, here, let's go back here.
Come here, come here.
Wait, let's think about it.
Let's think about it.
What could it be? What could it be?
Rope, not scissors, handcuffs.
Do you have any guesses as to what he could be trying to tell us?
Medieval torture?
No.
No?
Uh, one more guess maybe?
One more, one more.
Rope, scissors, handcuffs.
Those are the things.
Good girl.
Hootie's going to tie us
to our PC session stream, tie us, handcuff us and threaten us with scissors if we don't stream.
Oh, I thought I had that one.
Okay, um... I wonder, maybe, maybe three? Maybe it's not three.
Maybe there's more.
No, there has to be. There's not enough space here.
Another clue? Another clue?
Do you see anything red?
I see red, but we're not quite...
Not the bear.
Hey, are 100 behind you?
Hey, what's that behind you?
Huh?
Oh, there's a little friend here.
Not-- not a friend. No, that chill wasn't about friend. No, no, no, friend, friend, go away, go away, go away.
Not-- not a friend. No, that chill wasn't about friend. No, no, friend, go away!
Little friend...
Oh, inside Hootie! Hootie-- Hootie, it does have a food see.
So there are four.
What do you-- What's that?
I think I know what it is.
Do you know what it is, girl?
I was going to say Hootie's going to get rid of friend once and for all, but maybe I'm wrong.
Is that it?
That's what I thought.
That's pretty dark, girl.
That is wrong with you.
Um...
Um, well. Okay, how about...
Let me take a guess.
Could it be that Hootie wants to make friendship bracelets?
Nah.
What?
Of course. No.
No, Hootie is precious.
Friendship bracelet? Hootie, where are your beads?
Friendship bracelets? Hootie, where are your beads?
Where are your beads? What friendship bracelets are you making?
No, no, no, the ones that stream, you know?
No, no, no, the ones that use string, you know?
Real ones? No, the ones that are not.
Real ones? What kind of-- The ones that use cute colored thread and a rope used to tie up kidnapping victims.
Real ones? The ones that use cute colored thread and a rope used to tie up kidnapping victims.
Yeah, you don't need-- Wait, what?
You don't need beads for those. No, no, one thing, you know, you do the knot and it becomes a V.
You don't need beads for those. No, you do the knot and it becomes a V.
You know, and you use the special foam thingy, but it's like colorful soft thread to make it pink and purple and...
You know, and you use the special foam thingy with colorful soft thread to make it pink and purple and...
I know, is that cute?
A rope.
That's very-- That's very cute, Hootie. It's A-for-A for Hootie.
That's very cute, Hootie. It's A-for-effort for Hootie.
A for effort.
Good job. I'm sorry, Hootie, and good job.
That's a very kind gesture.
Good job to you, Gar Gura.
Good job to you, Gura.
I did my best. You did a very good job.
Didn't you, little Gar Gura? What a-- come here, come here, come here, come here, come here.
Didn't you, little Gar Gura? What a-- Come here, come here, come here, come here.
Well, thank you, kind audience member.
Thank you, Mumei!
Thank you for having me!
I will see you...
In your dreams.
In my dreams?
I'm going to go to sleep right now.
Okay, good night.
Good night! Thank you, Gura.
Bye-bye!
Man, I should really keep inventory of all the stuff I have here.
What else do I have?
Oh, yeah.
My gavel.
I totally forgot about this thing.
Oh, I totally forgot about this thing.
Here, do you want to Don-don?
Don-don!
Oh, hi!
You're finally awake.
Welcome!
I brought you guys outside, yes, dragged you into the sun.
Um, I brought you to these ancient ruins in a distant land that I found.
Uh, I think I'm the only one who's been coming here ever since this civilization fell.
Not sure how it fell.
Before you ask, it wasn't me, I do know that.
It wasn't me, all of this was not my doing, it wasn't my fault.
Look around!
Look how magnificent it is here.
Or, maybe I guess it was, but still pretty cool in a different way.
It looks like nature took over, there's a bunch of shrubs and moss and leaves...
But it's not gone as quite yet.
Not yet.
Still mine.
I do have some things to show you.
I found some things.
You want to see?
You want to see? Do you want to see?
Well, you have to, I'm taking you with me. Let's go!
Come on, come.
Okay.
I have dug a little hole here, kind of like my own little excavation site.
Um, there's some artifacts in here that I wanted to show you guys and I thought maybe we could figure out what the heck kind of civilization this was by looking at what was left behind.
Let's take a look-see here.
I gotta...
I got to kneel down.
Let's see, let's see, let's see.
Oh, first thing... This!
What is this?
What is it? What the... What the... Oh.
Wait, what does that look like? That looks magical.
It got some Egyptian hieroglyphs?
We're not in Egypt.
Maybe somebody went on vacation and and took it back or something.
What does that say?
I don't remember how to read this. Can any of you decode this?
If you can figure out what it says, please share.
With the hashtag, or you figure it out, share it in chat.
Probably isn't something too important.
Hm, interesting.
All right. Well, I guess we know that this civilization could travel a bit.
What else do we got? What else do we got?
Ooh, do you guys know what this is?
Have you ever seen this before?
It looks like a cup.
It is a cup, but not just any old cup.
It's a Pythagorean cup.
Have you heard of it?
It was basically a practical joke from like the 6th century BC.
I will explain it to you, I'll show you.
See? Inside the cup, there's a column here.
In the column there's a little pipe, a little hole that goes and it empties out at the bottom.
So if you're filling this with some type of fluid, if it goes past the column, the liquid will start to flow and will flow out of the cup and spill onto you, spill onto whoever is holding the cup.
I think it was to discourage people from being greedy and drinking drinking too much.
Oh, well, I can show you. I happen to have some berry juice. Hold on.
See? Berry juice.
Yeah, I'll show you. They fill it up.
Oh, it's full.
See?
And... Oh!
Oh, no, I... Oh, watch out, watch out, watch out!
Oh, that won't do that.
That's okay.
Gets a little red stain on your on your dress shirt.
Maybe awkward to explain...
Explain how you got that.
Yeah, that's how it works.
Why why is this here?
It has an owl, too.
What are the chances? Why is this here?
Did somebody take a vacation to Greece?
And bring it back?
Maybe?
Are we learning anything?
Have we fig- are we figuring anything out here?
What else do we have?
Ooh, what's this?
Ooh, that's heavy.
Look!
What is this?
It's a Viking sword.
It's a really old Viking sword.
It's freaking huge!
Wait.
Is it bigger than me? Hold on.
Is it?
No, not quite.
It's pretty big, though.
How people carry this? Whoever- whoever this belonged to must have been a lot bigger than me.
Look.
My god, it's huge!
It's okay, I'm strong though. I can...
Ow!
My goodness, it's so cool, though. The Vikings.
Nobody visited Denmark.
Maybe...
nobody visited Denmark. Maybe Denmark visited here.
Did this ancient civilization fall because the Vikings visited?
Maybe, or maybe someone did visit Denmark.
I think it's more interesting to think that the Vikings came in and raised this city,
civilization.
So we're going to go with that.
So we learned something.
We learned something, I guess.
Is there anything else in here?
Anything else? We learned how it's uh if the civilization fell,
but what what what civilization was it?
What's this doing here?
Who the heck is this?
Who the heck...
Who's this?
Actually, you look kind of familiar.
Oh, I know you.
Oh, I remember you all. Good times, good times! How you been?
Probably not well.
Interesting. I guess it makes sense to find human remains at an excavation site.
I guess that makes sense.
Um, I'm just gonna put you back.
Um, nice to see you again.
I don't think we can figure out what civilization this was based on all of that.
Why are these things here?
How did this happen?
You know what? It might have been me.
This might be my stuff.
Oh yeah, yeah, this is my stuff!
Oh wait, wait, wait, wait, I I left this stuff here.
This is my secret stash! Oh, it's good I found it again.
I had a bunch of interesting things to show you.
How to explain it?
Do I still want this though?
Don't any of you want these things?
Maybe I can sell them.
I wonder how much they're worth.
Am I allowed to sell that skull?
I'm sure it's fine.
Look out for it on Moon Bay later.
Anyways, anyways, I think that's enough uh can we get updates again?
Ouy! Okay, that's enough education.
I think for one stream or your brain's craving something else. That was boring, right?
Are you craving pretty colors, and dancing, and and singing, and magic? Would that satisfy your brain?
Well, good for you!
We are now going to enter these singing performance, dancing part of the 3D debut.
I have prepared quite a few performances for you guys.
Um, I should probably go get ready for those.
I will be back to prepare both physically and mentally. This is going to be fine.
Okay, I'll be back. See you in a second.
She lost her brother a month ago
His picture on the wall
And it reminds me
When she brings me coffee, her smile
I wish I could be with her till my last day
She said she gave all her love to me
We dreamt a new life, some place to be at peace
But things changed, suddenly
I lost my dreams in this disaster
I'm crying, missing my lover
I don't have the power on my side forever
Oh, where is my lover? And I got no power
I'm standing alone, no way, calling out your name
I said I gave all my love to you
We dreamt a new house, some place to be at peace
But things changed, suddenly, I lost my dreams in this disaster
she lost her brother a month ago
his picture on the wall
and it reminds me
when she brings me coffee, her smile
i wish i could be with her until my last day
she said she gave all her love to me
we dreamt a new life
some place to be at peace
but things changed, suddenly i lost my dreams in this disaster
i'm crying
missing my lover
i don't have the power on my side forever
oh where is my lover and i got no power
i'm standing alone, no way, calling out your name
i said i gave all my love to you
we dreamt a new house
some place to be at peace
but things changed, suddenly
i lost my dreams in this disaster
we don't know what is wrong tonight
everybody's got no place to hide
no one's left and there's no one to go on
all i know is my life is gone
i'm crying, missing my lover
i don't have the power on my side forever
oh where is my lover and i got no power
i'm standing alone, no way
calling out your name
Ta-da! That was Call Your Name.
I hope you enjoyed and didn't feel too much English.
Um, I just had a realization that all of the songs I'm going to perform today are kind of depressing.
But I'm fine! Everything's fine!
But now, I will have guests join me for some performances, they will join me for this very emo section of the debut...
But now, I will have guests join me for some performances, for this very emo section of the debut...
...the 3D debut! Uh, but who could it be?
Who will be next? Stay tuned to find out!
I mean, I- I should ready myself. Okay, I'm ready, I'm ready.
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I talk about what I've been thinking for a long time?
友達に戻れたらこれ以上はもう望まないさ
If we can go back to being friends, I'll ask for nothing more.
君がそれでいいなら僕だってそれで構わないさ
If you're okay with that, I don't mind either.
嘘つきの僕が吐いた 反対言葉の愛のうた
A love song of contradictory words sung by me, a liar.
今日はこっちの地方はどしゃぶりの晴天でした
Today, the weather in this area was a clear sunny sky with downpour.
昨日もずっと暇で一日満喫してました
Yesterday was also totally free, enjoying the whole day.
別に君のことなんて考えてないかなんて
It's not like I was thinking about you or anything.
いやでもちょっと本当は考えてたかもなんて
Well, maybe I actually was, just a little.
メリーゴーランドみたいに回る 僕の頭ん中はもうグルグルさ
Spinning like a merry-go-round, my head is all dizzy.
この両手から零れそうなほど 君に貰った愛はどこに捨てよう?
From these hands, so much love you gave me, where should I throw it away?
限界のある消耗品なんて僕は 要らないよ
I have no need for consumables with limits.
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I talk about what I've been thinking for a long time?
姿は見えないのに言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
You can't see the shape, but you can only see the words.
僕が知らないことがあるだけで気が狂いそうだ
I feel like losing my mind just knowing there are things I don't know.
ぶら下がった感情が 綺麗なのかな汚いのかも
Are these dangling emotions beautiful or dirty?
この両手から零れそうなほど
On the verge of spilling from these hands,
君に貰った愛はどこに捨てよう?
where should I throw away the love you gave me?
限界のある消耗品なんて僕は要らないよ
I have no need for consumables with limits.
鍵のかかる部屋のなかに閉じこもって
Locking myself away in a locked room,
揺れないよ
I won't waver.
僕がずっと前から思ってる事を話そうか
Shall I talk about what I've been thinking for a long time?
姿は見えないのに言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
You can't see the shape, but you can only see the words.
僕が知らないことがあるだけで気が狂いそうだ
I feel like losing my mind just knowing things I don't know.
ぶら下がった感情が 綺麗なのかな汚いのかも
Are these dangling emotions beautiful or dirty?
僕はまだ分からない まだ分からない
I still don't know yet, I still don't know.
言葉の裏の裏が見えるまで待つからさ
I'll wait until I can see the hidden truth behind your words.
待つぐらいならいいじゃないか
Waiting a little while wouldn't be so bad, would it?
進む君と止まった僕の
You moving forward, and me standing still—
縮まらない隙を何で埋めようよ
what should I use to fill the gap that won't close?
まだ素直に言葉に出来ない僕は
I'm still a coward who can't speak my true feelings,
天性の弱虫さ
born with an innate cowardice.
この両手から零れそうなほど
It's about to spill right out of my hands—
君に渡す愛を誰に譲ろう
this love meant for you, who should I hand it over to?
そんなどこにも宛てがあるわけないだろ
There's no place like that anywhere, of course not!
まだ待つよ もういいかい
I'll keep waiting. Are you ready yet?
やった！ Congratulation!
Yay! Congratulations!
Thank you, Towa-sama!
That's right. I invited Towa-sama
because of the history we have together, our memories.
because of the history we share together, our memories.
We played APEX together, then we had English lessons together, and now we sing together!
いっぱいね、あのAPEXしたりとか英語クイズとか一緒にやったよみたいな、だから呼んだよみたいなの言ってくれました。
She said things like, "We did a lot of things together like playing Apex and English quizzes, so that's why I invited you."
え、そしてね、え、からお、え、そうなの、配信ではそうやって遊んでたけどカラオケに行ったことあるんだよね、日本のカラオケ。
And then, you know, we used to hang out like that on stream, but we've actually gone to karaoke together—Japanese karaoke!
でもその時はね、Mumeiが「トワ様、恥ずかしい」って言ってトワと一緒に歌ってくれなかったの！
But back then, Mumei said, "Towa-sama, I'm embarrassed," and wouldn't sing with me!
でも今日は一緒に歌ってくれました！ Today together song! Yes!
But today she sang with me! Today together song! Yes!
Yes, you know? Towa-sama? Do you remember English?
Ohhh... A little.
え、Mumeiは日本語喋れる？
Can Mumei speak Japanese?
あ、少し日本語喋れます。
I can speak a little Japanese.
お、うまい！
Oh, great!
うん、だけど良いアイデア。How about we make each other's each other's say things in English and Japanese?
Yeah, I have a good idea. How about we make each other say things in English and Japanese?
So I will say something in English, and Towa-sama will repeat, and Towa-sama will say something in Japanese, and I will repeat. Yes?
Okay, Towa-sama, please explain in Japanese. 日本語お願いします。
Okay, Towa-sama, please explain in Japanese. Please explain in Japanese.
はい、OKです。え、今Mumeiがね、え、いいこと思いついたと、え、Mumeiとトワでお互いに言わせたい日本語、英語を言うのはどうかなみたいな感じでやってみようって、
Yes, okay! So Mumei just came up with a great idea: how about we try having Mumei and me say lines in Japanese and English that we want each other to say?
でトワから言っていいよっていうことで、え、今からお互いに言わせたいセリフを言いたいと思います。
She said, "Towa, you can go first," so starting now, we'll each say a line we want the other to say!
え、何にしようかな、なんかトワからいいって言ってくれたから、え、なんでもいいのかな？
Eh, what should I choose? Since Towa said I could go first, anything is fine?
Anything! なんでもいいらしい！
Anything! Apparently anything is fine!
と言ったらやっぱりこれでしょう。え、Repeat after me.
If so, then it has to be this. Eh, repeat after me.
Okay. お帰りなさい。ご飯にする？
Okay. Welcome home. Will you have dinner?
お風呂にする？
Will you take a bath?
それとも私？ Go!
Or... is it me? Go!
お帰りなさい。ご飯にする？お風呂にする？それとも…私？私！
Welcome home. Will you have dinner? Will you take a bath? Or... me? Me!
かわいい！
So cute!
Okay. I'm going to make Towa-sama say something kind of similar. Okay, okay. Repeat after me.
Hi, honey!
How was work today? Are you tired? Let me rub your shoulders.
おけおけ、任せて。Hi, honey! How was work today?
Okay, okay, leave it to me. Hi, honey! How was work today?
Are you tired? Let me love your shoulders.
Perfect! You're welcome international fan!
Perfect! You're welcome, international fans!
Want to take a picture together? Oh, okay, okay, we take a picture.
Want to take a picture together? Oh, okay, okay, let's take a picture.
OK、何しよう？どっち？ OK! OK! This? OK!
Okay, what should we do? Which one? Okay! Okay! This? Okay! Hi!
And heart! Oh, heart! OK, OK, OK! Yeah, yeah, perfect!
And a heart! Oh, a heart! Okay, okay, okay! Yeah, yeah, perfect!
ありが…!
Thank...
ありがとー！
Thank you!
Nice, nice!
Thank you so much Towa-chan, 来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much, Towa-chan, for coming!
いや、こちらこそ呼んでくれてありがと！ Thank you for inviting me!
No, thank you for inviting me!
ということでがんばってね！
So, do your best!
ありがと！
Thank you!
バイバ～イ！バイバ～イ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
0と1が交差する地点
Where 0 and 1 intersect,
間違いだらけの コミュニケーション
a communication full of mistakes.
アナタの名前は 何ですか?
What is your name?
10文字以内で 答エ ヨ
Answer in 10 characters or less.
過去と未来が 交差する地点
Where past and future intersect,
行く宛を失った 現在地
the current location that lost its destination.
アナタはどうして 生きているの?
Why are you living?
100文字以内で 答エ ヨ
Answer in 100 characters or less.
昼と夜が 交差する地点
Where day and night intersect,
誰かに会いたくて 会えなくて
wanting to meet someone, but unable to,
ワタシの名前は 何ですか?
what is my name?
10文字以内で 教えて
Tell me in 10 characters or less.
嘘と本当が 交差する地点
Where lies and truth intersect,
呼吸が止まりそうな 閉塞感
a suffocating sense of confinement.
ワタシはどうして 生きているの?
Why am I living?
100文字以内で 教えて
Tell me in 100 characters or less.
好き 嫌い 好き 嫌いの繰り返しで
Repeating like, dislike, like, dislike,
疲れきった愛は もういらない
I no longer need exhausted love.
時間だけいつも 通り過ぎてく
Only time always passes by,
1秒ごとに 崩れていく 世界
a world collapsing every second.
歪んだ景色に 塗りつぶされた
Painted over in a distorted scenery,
真実はいらない 偽りでいいの
I don't need truth, falsehoods are fine.
自分だけどこか 取り残された
Only I was left behind somewhere,
色のない世界 夢に見た 世界
a colorless world, a world seen in a dream.
傷んだ果実を 捨てる ことすら
Even throwing away bruised fruit,
出来ないなら 傍にいてほしくて
if I can't, I want you by my side.
Congratulation! おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Thank you Korone-senpai! Thank you for coming!
Yes, I invited Korone-senpai because she is how I got into Hololive, how I discovered it.
Yes, I invited Korone-senpai because she's how I got into Hololive, how I discovered it.
And I chose this particular song because it's about being lonely and sad, but we're not lonely or sad in Hololive, so we're all happy singing it!
And I chose this song because it's about being lonely and sad, but we're not lonely or sad in Hololive, so we're all happy singing it!
Thank you, thank you!
I am happy with single...
I am happy singing with...
sing Korone senpai!
Korone-senpai!
I am happy singing with Korone-senpai!
I want to play with you more!
あそびたい！ あそびたい！
I want to play! I want to play!
お、先輩！ 野球が好きですか？
Oh, Senpai! Do you like baseball?
野球大好き！
I love baseball!
本当？ お待たせ for you, I have baseball equipment!
Really? Hold on, for you, I have baseball equipment!
本当に？ 野球ができるプレイよ。 Here, here.
Really? Here's your bat to play baseball. Here, here.
Here is your bat!
バット？
A bat?
これバット！ Yes, it's a bat for baseball!
It's a bat! Yes, it's a bat for baseball!
Baseball bat? うんうん！
Baseball bat? Mhm!
うん、OK
Hmm, okay.
Are you ready? You got it, you got it.
Now, see, you need a ball though. I don't know if we have a ball.
Where is it? Where is it? Oh!
Perfect!
Come here, Hootzie!
How to catch him? How to catch him?
Got him!
Hootzie... sweet ball? This is a ball?
So this is a ball?
We will use it as a ball, Hootzie!
My Hootzie!
それを打つの？
You're gonna hit that?
It's okay, it's okay.
Okay, okay. Don't worry, don't worry.
Ready? Are you ready?
Okay.
Ah? Okay.
One, two, three...
There was no power in that!
なんか痛そうだよ、Mumei。かわいそう。
That looks painful, Mumei. Poor thing.
No, no, no, don't, don't worry. Does it hurt?
痛くない？
Doesn't it hurt?
痛くない
It doesn't hurt.
本当じゃあ
Really? Then...
Big swing!
I have to catch... Oh, okay. Big swing. She wants to... One, two, three...
Nice! 痛くないか？
Nice! Doesn't it hurt?
本当に、本当に痛くない？
Really, really doesn't it hurt?
本当に痛くない！
It really doesn't hurt!
痛くない？ See, he's happy!
Doesn't hurt? See, he's happy!
本当だ！幸せそう。
That's true! He looks happy.
大丈夫そう。
Looks like he'll be fine.
はい、おいで、おいで。
Come here, come here.
Oh, do you want to hold him? Yes.
He's so cute, right? Oh, you can hold him.
Oh, that's cute. Puppy.
That's too cute.
Oh my hootz! Too cute! Kawaii sugi!
Oh my hootz! Too cute! Too cute!
I want to take a picture!
Take a picture! Take a picture! Take a picture!
Come here, come here, both of you is so cute.
Come here, both of you are so cute.
せーの、チーズ！
Ready, cheese!
Oh, so cute!
Oh, one more! One more shot!
Okay, okay?
Throw up! Up! Up! Up!
Perfect! Okay.
せーの、チーーズ！ Hootzi! Yes!
Ready, cheeeese! Hootzi! Yes!
Okay, Mumei, last shot! One last one.
On his nest! Back in the nest! Perfect!
Oh, I love you too, Hootzie!
Okay, okay, せーの、チーズ！
Okay, okay, ready, cheese!
Oh, Mumei, bye. Oh, goodbye.
Gorillisan, bye. 気いてくれてありがとうございました。
Gorillisan, bye. Thank you for listening.
こちらこそありがとね。
Thank you too.
Bye-bye. Oh, she's taking Hootzi with her.
Uh-oh, he'll be fine. It's okay.
ずッと夢見てた僕になれたかな
I wonder if I've become the me I always dreamed of seeing,
とうに帰れないところまで来たみたい
having come to a place from which there is no returning.
自分の足で二段飛ばしてそうもっと先へ駆け出していけるはずだからrun away
I should be able to run even further ahead, taking two steps at a time on my own two feet, so run away.
深くなる傷を縫い付け繋ぐパス軸に纏り出す
Stitching up the deepening wounds, I wrap them around the connecting path's axis.
慣れた痛み、焦る呼吸とビート気づかないふりをしてまた一人
With familiar pain, hurried breathing, and beat, pretending not to notice, I'm alone again.
何が正当？ないない永劫誰が間違えた対価払うの
What is justified? There is no eternity. Who pays the price for who got it wrong?
あなたが嫌いなあいつはきっとただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
That person you hate so much is surely just incorrect "simply because of that."
0点だって提言したって全然納得できない理由も最前線はいつだってここだった最善策は最初からなかった
Even if I'm told it's zero points and I can't accept the reason at all, the front line was always here, and the best plan was never there from the start.
緩やかに崩壊壊れていく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks,
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
as if slowly, slowly choking, the me of yesterday is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽く
Slowly and gently, our scattered ennui...
ぐらりん君にきこえるのは僕が知らない声になっていく
When I hear you speak unethically, it turns into a voice I don't know.
幼い頃から気付けば傍にいた
Since I was young, when I noticed, you were always by my side,
まるで空気のように僕は君とぎゅっと手をつないで
just like air, I firmly held your hand in mine.
楽しいことも涙も僕は君に話して聞かせた
Cheerful things, tears, I told them all to you.
僕を笑う人や貶す声が聞こえないように君は歌った
You sang so I wouldn't hear people laughing or jeering at me.
この声を君が受信また夜毎投影されてく憂い
You received this voice; every night, worries are projected.
使い捨てだっていって言って腐っても止まらないハイファイ、ツァイトガイスト
Even if I say I was used and discarded to rot, the unstoppable high-fi zeitgeist...
一周巡る間のたった一瞬だけでも交わる鼓動、音、繋ぐ色
For just one moment in one round, heartbeats cross, noises, connecting colors.
次は僕が君に歌うから
Next time, I will sing for you.
緩やかに崩壊壊れていくゆるりゆるり首を締めるように昨日の僕が殺されていく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks, as if slowly, slowly choking, the me of yesterday is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れ飽くぐらりん君にきこえるのは僕が知らない声になっていく
Slowly and gently, our scattered ennui... When I hear you speak unethically, it turns into a voice I don't know...
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
It seems that I've gotten used to just living a dream
とうに帰れないところまで来たみたい
It feels like I've reached the point of no return
自分の足で二段飛ばしてそうもっと先へ
I jump up two stairs with my own feet
走っていけるはずだから run away
And because it looked like I'd keep going from there, I ran away
深くなる傷を縫い付け
After stitching the deepening wound
繋ぐパス軸に廻り出す
The paths are connecting and springing away
慣れた痛み、焦る呼吸とビート
The usual pain, the beat and my breathing quickens
気付かないふりしてまた一人
Act so though I don't feel anything alone again
何が正当？ないない永劫
Who is right? There never is one
誰が間違った対価払うの
Who was wrong? Shouldn't they be compensated?
あなたが嫌いなあいつはきっと
That one you hate so much is surely just "like that"
ただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
Just wrong for "that"
0点だって提言したって全然納得できない理由も
I advise it's zero points, but it's not accepted at all
最前線はいつだってここだった
The frontier was always here
最善策は最初からなかった
The best way wasn't there in the first place
緩やかに崩壊壊れていく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように
As if it's slowly, slowly choking
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Me of yesterday is being killed off
緩やかに離れ離れ飽う嫌
Slowly and gently, our scattered ennui
ぐらりぐらり君にきこえるのは
When I hear you speak unethically
僕が知らない声になっていく
It turns into a voice I don't know
幼い頃から気付いたら傍にいた
Since I was young when I realized it was always by my side
まるで空気のように僕は君とぎゅっと手を繋いで
Just like air, I firmly held your hand in mine
楽しいことも涙も僕は君に話して聞かせた
Cheerful things, tears, I told them all to you
ムメイ、おめでとうコングラッチュレーションズ on the new me!
Mumei, congratulations on the new me!
てんきゅー、とても嬉しかったんだ、yay!
Thank you, I'm very glad, yay!
I am waited for senpai!
Because she was so nice to us when we first debuted!
To Council, she's been so welcoming to EN!
And... and she made me a berry house in Minecraft!
So... I... I... I wanted to invite her...
A berry house, ok?
A berry house, okay?
You remember?
浴衣が似合うね。
Yukata looks good, ne.
同じもいいね。
Matches well too.
じゃあここでムメイにわからないことを言ってるところでね、えー...
Now, Mumei said something incomprehensible earlier...
No title.
うん。
Mm.
Beautiful Perfect No Titleは...
Beautiful Perfect No Title is...
ナナシームメイだからムメイでNo Title?
Nanashi Mumei, therefore Mumei, No Title?
どう？
How?
あー、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
なるほど。
I see.
Ah, I didn't think of that.
That's genius!
偶然？
Coincidence?
え、トマトマホ？
Eh, tomato-mato?
うちの先輩 genius!
Our senpai is genius!
Genius! お、頭がいい！
Genius! Oh, head is good!
Yay! You genius! おー。
Yay! You're genius. Oh.
ムメイもgenius!
Mumei is genius.
I'm genius without no...
Genius!
Genius is... あ、そうだ。コロネから...
Genius is... Oh, that's right. Korone from...
あのコロネさんがね...
That Korone-san, you know...
あ、フーチ！あ、フーチ、フーチが！
Oh, Fuzichan! Fuzichan is here!
フーチ！
Fuzichan!
フーチ、ちゃんと休憩した？
Fuzichan, did you take a proper break?
休憩した？
Did you take a break?
したよ。Yeah, I think he's ready to have some more fun!
Yeah, I think he's ready to have some more fun.
帰るよ、じゃあね。
He's going home. Bye-bye.
Yeah, yeah. 仕事終わり？
Yeah, yeah. Work's over?
No, no, no, no, no, come back, come back!
Come back here!
No, no, no, time for more fun!
まだ仕事とか...
Not a job though.
え、それ、さっきやってたけど、飛ぶ？
What, fly?
Fuchi, fly?
あー、want to see him fly?
Oh, you want to see him fly?
Fly? Fuchi?
Yeah, we have to help him fly though.
ポッツさん、スポーツやりますか？
Fuzichan, do sports?
お、っしゃ！
Oh, yeah!
Perfect! We're going to punt him so that he flies.
We're going to kick him.
フーチ？Yeah.
Fuzichan? Yeah.
大丈夫？
You okay?
全然感じない、痛みを。
Not really feeling any pain.
感じない。
Not feeling it.
痛みを感じない。
Not feeling pain.
じゃあしようよ、しようよ、しようよ。
Shall we show you? Shall we show you? Shall we show you?
フーチ？
Fuchi?
うわー！
Oh!
フーチ？すごい！すごい！すごい！
Fuchi? Amazing! Amazing! Amazing!
He looks like... そうに泣いてる。
He looks like he's crying.
泣いてる泣いてる。
Oh, he's crying.
He's okay!
大丈夫で。
He's okay.
じゃあ、フォカも、please, kick him!
Okay, then, Foka, please kick him.
Kick him! Kick him!
どうやってるの？
How do you do that?
Here we go! うわー！
Here we go! Whoa!
Perfect!
フーチ！フーチ！
Fuchi! Fuchi!
フーチの膝。
Fuchi's knee.
Oh, poor Fuzichan!
Forget it. Forget it.
He's fine. Come here.
恐ろしい子だ。
What a scary child.
Oh, very good. I think I think that's enough of...
今日 für heute.
for today.
But first actually...
How about a photo?
Do you want to take a photo?
写真！写真！
Picture! Picture!
Let's take a photo!
Okay, one second.
Okay, okay.
Hold on!
I'm holding it!
All right, ready?
Ready, set, cheese!
Cheese!
One more!
One more, one more!
What should we do?
Woo!
Aw!
Ready, set, cheese!
Perfect, perfect!
Thank you for the senpai!
Thank you, thank you, arigatou gozaimashita!
- Here's a toast!
Thank you!
Bye-bye!
Shall we go home?
Okay, let's go.
Daijoubu.
Daijoubu, daijoubu!
Yeah, Mumei!
Go!
Let's go back!
Mogu mogu...
Bye-bye!
Mogu mogu mogu mogu mogu...
It'll be fine.
It's okay.
Um, you know,
I have some more announcements to give you guys.
Uh, let's go to the treehouse.
I'll tell you there.
Oh no, that's right.
That's right.
Ta-da!
We're back in the treehouse.
I thought we could warm ourselves up a little bit just before the last song.
Sure would be nice to have some fire outside.
Contained,
you know, contained in something,
and then it could produce a light source and it could guide us to a hot spring or a volcano or something.
How could we get...
something like that?
Oh duh, my lantern!
Oh, how silly of me!
I'm so handy-dandy for such things.
You guys don't have one, do you?
Suckers.
Just kidding.
You're in luck!
Because now I can offer you...
A lantern of your own!
Just like mine!
Wow!
Incredible!
That's right, merchandise!
It's merchandise time.
Um, yes, you can get a lantern like mine.
Except this one's made of silicone.
And there's no fire.
And it doesn't produce heat.
So it's not hot to the touch.
But it produces light.
That's pretty nice, right?
That's pretty nice.
You can put it next to your bed.
You can put it on your desk.
Um, anywhere you need a little extra light in your...
in your life.
Um, it can protect you from monsters in your closet.
Uh, or can show you whatever's watching you in the dark.
Or...
You don't really need it for that, right, team?
But, yeah.
Lantern.
Just like mine.
If you want it, yes, 3D merchandise.
Who could have expected?
Oh my gosh, yes,
I'm the best at at shilling.
Okay.
Anyways, yes, uh, please feel free to get one if you need it, if you want it.
Um, oh god, okay.
That's it for the merchandise.
Um, but I got one more song for you guys.
Shall I go do it?
Shall I go go there to do it?
I I'll do that.
Let's go.
Follow me.
an adorable star
we can see from afar
but a truth it belies
all who enters her dies
hear the beating of wings
as the pendulum swings
and we can't believe
it's ever gonna end
you know blood is thicker than water
but you just want everyone to get along
for the candles in the darkness
burning up the sorrow
there's no end to sadness
we didn't learn
for the broken hearted people
diamonds now surround us
so out of our mind
leave the past behind
we're a binary heart
tear each other apart
growing from the same stem
they were us, we were them
on a course to collide
is it strength not to hide?
let the politics decide you're not a friend
A binary star we can see from afar
But a truth it belies, all who enter her dies
Hear the beating of wings as the pendulum swings
And we can't believe it's ever gonna end
You know blood is thicker than water
But you just want everyone to get along
For the candles in the darkness
Burning up the sorrow
There's no end to sadness we didn't learn
For the broken hearted people
Diamonds now surround us
So out of our mind, leave the past behind
Binary...
A centrifugal force, pushing us far away
That's our eternity
Binary...
We can't escape the force, crushing us
Gravity is our eternity
A binary star we can see from afar
But a truth it belies, all who enter her dies
Hear the beating of wings as the pendulum swings
And we can't believe it's ever gonna end
You know blood is thicker than water
But you just want everyone to get along
For the candles in the darkness
Burning up the sorrow
There's no end to sadness we didn't learn
For the broken hearted people
Diamonds now surround us
So out of our mind, leave the past behind
Binary...
A centrifugal force, pushing us far away
That's our eternity
Binary...
We can't escape the force, crushing us
Gravity is our eternity
For the candles in the darkness
Burning up the sorrow
There's no end to sadness we didn't learn
For the broken hearted people
Diamonds now surround us
So out of our mind, leave the past behind
For the candles in the darkness
Burning up the sorrow
There's no end to sadness we didn't learn
For the broken hearted people
Diamonds now surround us
So out of our mind, leave the past behind
Binary...
A centrifugal force, pushing us far away
That's our eternity
Binary...
We can't escape the force, crushing us
Gravity is our eternity